# Jared Ryan

jaredryan.netlify.app | github.com/jaredryan jryantennis@gmail.com | 559-348-3595 | Jupiter, FL (Remote)

# Summary

Fullstack software engineer. 5 years of experience, mostly w/JS languages. Better at frontend.

**Skills**: JS, React, Node, Express, GraphQL, MongoDB, SQL, Kubernetes, Python, Java, Ruby **Technical Traits**: Curious to try new things. Enjoys PR reviews, refactoring. Design-oriented. **Personal Traits**: Organized. Empathetic. Good listener. Outspoken. Personable.

# Experience

#### MANTL, Activations, Software Engineer II

Jupiter, FL (Remote) | 2021 - 2023

- Mentored a few engineers on frontend work and owned crucial frontend features, gaining a reputation for good PR reviews, careful testing, troubleshooting, good design and flows
- Co-led work on introducing a design-component library that integrates with the prior one
- Co-led work on an automated testing pipeline: the pipeline itself, testing framework, database seeding / cleanup, tests, and teaching others how to contribute
- Proactively worked with cross-team stakeholders to identify, prioritize, and complete work to reduce number of days on our "activation" flow (time from request to completion)

#### IBM, Cloud Pak for Data, Software Engineer II

San Jose, CA | 2019 - 2021

- Refactored entire frontend for user management, which evolved to a small leadership role as work expanded and required additional engineers
- Architected user management technical solutions with product and backend lead, considering security, performance, sizing, business value, and usability
- Co-created conceptual models and user flows with design, providing guidance on attributes and relationships between users, roles, permissions, and groups
- Planned projects with 1, 3, and 6 month cycles, executed via Agile in 2-week sprints

## IBM, AppID, Software Engineer I

Austin, TX | 2018 - 2019

- Prototyped a fullstack application in React, Node, and Python showcasing all uses of ApplD, which was leveraged for sales pitches and demos
- Adapted to multiple technologies and protocols to quickly debug issues: OAuth, OpenID, Node, Angular, Java, Android, Swift, Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins, Github, Zenhub

#### NTR, Web Developer

Berkeley, CA (Remote) | 2018 - 2022

- Sole developer on a web app for collecting, grading, and anonymizing peer feedback, which has been used by 600 students, across 7 schools, generating 6K evaluations
- Collaborated with non-technical UC Berkeley professor to define product requirements and designs, then again for updates and new features over the 4 years before handoff
- Learned troubleshooting without access to clients, and maintenance practices

## Education

UC Berkeley, B.S. Bioengineering w/Computer Science Emphasis

2017

## Interests

Real estate, video games, food, beaches, journaling, playing sports, travel